Marco Cordeiro

<u>cordeirom@gmail.com</u> • Rio de Janeiro - Brazil • +55-21-9355-3414 https://br.linkedin.com/in/cordeirom

Objectives

IT Infrastructure analyst with over 20 years' experience, seeks position that will utilize strong project and team management skills. Strong experience in the IT infrastructure, security, project management and governance, IT contracting in public bodies, contract and supplier management, management of multidisciplinary teams, using methodologies such as SCRUM, ITIL, COBIT and PMI. Management of critical information business systems, telecommunications and datacenter components such as Virtualization, Blades, Storages and Backup Libraries. Has communication skills to collaborate in all levels of business while effectively managing systems, processes, operating procedures, and on-site and remote site documentation. Professional highly committed, motivated and with the versatility to work among different groups and deal with problems effectively.

Education

Fundação Getúlio Vargas – FGV -2012/2013 MBA – IT Management

Estacio de Sá University – 1997 / 2000 Information Technology – Computer Network - CRA-RJ 34.48909-6

CEFET – 1985 / 1987 Electronic technician - CREA-RJ 82.103728-2

Certifications

https://www.youracclaim.com/user/marco-cordeiro

MCP - Administering Windows Server 2012 MCSA – Windows Server 2012 – ID 14344919 ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management - ID 6092796 CompTIA Linux+ Certified – ID COMP001021233009 LPIC-1 Linux Administrator – ID LPI000389584 • • •

Experience

Montreal Informática - RJ |

IT Project Management - Agosto 2017 - Atual

Project to modernize the Help Desk and Service Desk areas of Detran-RJ. Evaluation of compliance with the ITIL framework, methodology design and definition of the project life cycle according to PMI good practices, prioritization and encapsulation of the strategic initiatives in the proposed management model, critical success factors and performance indicators for the projects, implementation of new service methodologies and procedures for creation and maintenance of a technical knowledge base to be used by the technical support and users, the adequacy of the support tool to the (GLPI) to support the processes and generation of dashboards with indicators, cultural dissemination and mentoring among the functional silos of the implementation of the PDCA cycle for continuous process improvement.

Nautitoy Entretenimentos - RJ | cjcmatos59@gmail.com

Product develepor Engineer - dezembro 2015 - janeiro 2017

Develop products and solutions with focus on entertainment market and education. These products are build using innovators technology on top of Arduinos and low level software and using new PaaS and laaS to build IoT devices to interact with each other's.

Procuradoria Geral do Estado - RJ | <u>hsfreire@pge.rj.gov.br</u> IT Manager 05/2009 – 12/2015

Manages the designs and plans of network communications systems and IT systems. Responsible for coordinating IT team. Oversees specifications and detailed schematics for network architecture. Insures that specific detailed information for hardware and software selection, implementation techniques and tools for the most efficient solution to meet business needs, including present and future capacity requirements, are provided. Directs the conducting of network design testing. Insures technical expertise in all areas of network and computer hardware and software interconnection and interfacing, such as routers, switches, firewalls, IPS/IDS, VMware, AD, etc. is maintained. Evaluates and reports on new communications technologies to enhance capabilities of the network.

Kmt Consult - RJ | vinod@ic.uff.br; peter.giallias@us.rothschild.com Network Consultant 01/1995 – 03/2008

Network and systems administration of Cisco, Checkpoint, Juniper, etc. and UNIX, Linux, Windows development and test environments and related production application deployment activities, incorporating best practices; identifying internal and external needs (architecture, scalability, physical requirements, etc.); installing, configuring, upgrading and maintaining network devices and servers, including switches, routers, firewalls, operating systems, intrusion detection systems, and TCP/IP services in accordance with established policies, procedures and service level agreements; monitoring, evaluating, identifying problems with hardware & software installation and operation and tuning the

• • •

system to achieve optimum performance; network availability and backups, applications, and application data security on the various systems and networks; working closely with customer, requirements, development, database, deployment and test personnel to deliver high quality software. Identifying internal and external needs (architecture, scalability, physical requirements, etc.), OSI model.

FS Electronics - NY / USA | pntanure@aol.com

Network Administrator 08/1993 – 09/1994

Installation and configuration of Novell Netware 3.12 & upgrade to Netware 4.x Network with NDS.Configured the critical Network components like Remote Booting, Printing, RAS (Remote Access Services). Protecting Network data, monitoring network performance management and optimization. Filtering users rights according to their need. Implementing Login security, File system. Planning and configuring Remote printing on Netware.

Skills

Knowledge in Cloud Infrastructure such as AWS, AZURE e Google Cloud.

In-depth knowledge in Linux, Windows Server (2008, 2012 and 2016).

In-depth knowledge in Directory services as Windows Active Directory, LDAP and NIS.

In-depth knowledge in Network services as DNS, DHCP, NFS, SAMBA, APACHE, NGINX, FTP.

In-depth knowledge in Virtualization as VMware, XEN, HYPER-V and CITRIX.

Security and Network Design and Implementation.

In-depth knowledge of WAN, LAN and Security Networks Operations.

In-depth knowledge in Routing and Switching.

Knowledge in Wireless network and protocols.

Knowledge in Shell Scripts, C, PHP and Python.

Knowledge in Mysql, Microsoft SQL server and PostgreSQL.

In-depth Knowledge of Routing Protocols (BGP, OSPF, EIGRP, IS-IS, RIP).

Knowledge in Security Firewalls as ASA, Palo Alto, Fortigate, Mcafee, IPTABLES.

Knowledge in VPNs Technologies such as IPSEC, SSL.

Knowledge in MPLS Networks.

In-depth Knowledge in layer 2 techonologies as Spanning-tree, Port-Security, CoS, DTP, Vlan, Trunking.

Knowledge in Multicast, MLD, PIM-SM, PIM-DM

Knowledge in System Management as SNMP, Syslog, EEM, Nagios, Zabix and CiscoWorks.

Deployment of routing protocols OSPF, BGP, EIGRP.

Supporting and troubleshooting several technologies and vendors.

Languages

- English Business fluency, Spanish Business fluency, Portuguese Native.